PABLO GUTIERREZ ELIZONDO

pablo.gtz.e.9@gmail.com | (+52) 55 8531 4610

Chemical Engineer from La Universidad Iberoamericana with experience in the Auto Industry, Energy, Fintech and Consumer Products. Focus on Business Operations & Strategy with ability to perform market research and data analysis to improve business decisions and process design and optimization. Strong interpersonal skills that allow to work alongside different teams from a variety of backgrounds to solve key problems.

EMPLOYMENT

NISSAN MOTOR CORPORATION

Mexico City, Mexico

Finance Sr Data Analyst

March 2023 - Present

- · Organized two strategic seminars for the region's VPs and Directors of Finance and IS/IT as a member of the Americas CFO Office, and initiated the region's first hackathon to address key data and AI challenges.
- · Led a cross-functional team to reduce expense approvals by 33% within a year. Used data analysis to identify and address bottlenecks, as well as to propose changes to the region's Delegation of Authority Policy. Additionally, I created a dashboard to visualize regional expense distribution.
- · Utilized AI and Python to analyze extensive qualitative data, providing strategic direction for CFO Office enablement activities and showcasing this process to encourage the transition from spreadsheets to advanced data analysis methods.

PLERK (YC S20)

Mexico City, Mexico

Business Operations & Strategy Sr Analyst

April 2022 - February, 2023

- · Used SQL to solve a credit card functionality issue, reducing losses by over \$30k by implementing safety measures and working with the CFO to reflect losses in financial statements.
- · Led an MVP rollout for Payment Advancement Loans, defining product features, process designs, costs, pricing, and compliance, gaining approval from key executives and serving 15-20% of the client base.
- Developed a new pricing model for subscription plans, creating logic for personalized experiences and enabling different modules, resulting in a 70% revenue increase in 4 months by guiding the development of a new SaaS platform through surveys and UI tests.

PROCTER & GAMBLE

Mexico City, Mexico

PRT (Product Research Testing) Project Leader

July 2020 - November 2021

- Led and created content for a global event showcasing Consumer Studies to 100+ members, achieving a 4.8/5 satisfaction rate and reducing event costs by \$20k by creating the event site.
- · Performed data analysis for consumer studies in Fabric Care Mexico, developed remote study processes during COVID-19, and created a PowerBI dashboard for regional data visualization, enhancing product performance and increasing production rates by 20%.

BRIGHT INC Mexico City, Mexico

Corporate Operations Intern

November 2018-July 2019

· Managed weekly overhead and expense preparations, updated expense reports for audits, and assisted with order planning, sales compensation, and insurance acquisition with teams from the USA and Mexico.

EDUCATION

Universidad Iberoamericana

Mexico City, Mexico

BS Chemical Engineering

- •Excellence Award in 2021 General Exam for Graduation of Chemical Engineering given to the best performers nationwide (4% of exam-takers).
- · 8.9/10 GPA

SKILLS & KNOWLEDGE

- · Languages: Spanish (Native). English (Advanced proficiency Level C1)
- · Advanced skills in Microsoft Office, Python, Tableau, and SQL. Experience with R, MatLab and JMP.